<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.gnome.NautilusDevel.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <name>Files</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_TW">檔案</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_HK">檔案</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_CN">文件</name>
  <name xml:lang="vi">Tập tin</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Файли</name>
  <name xml:lang="ug">ھۆججەتلەر</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Dosyalar</name>
  <name xml:lang="th">แฟ้ม</name>
  <name xml:lang="tg">Файлҳо</name>
  <name xml:lang="te">దస్త్రాలు</name>
  <name xml:lang="ta">கோப்புகள்</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Filer</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr@latin">Datoteke</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr">Датотеке</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Datoteke</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Súbory</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Файлы</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Fișiere</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt_BR">Arquivos</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Ficheiros</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Pliki</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਫਾਇਲਾਂ</name>
  <name xml:lang="or">ଫାଇଲଗୁଡିକ</name>
  <name xml:lang="oc">Fichièrs</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">Filer</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Bestanden</name>
  <name xml:lang="ne">फाइलहरू</name>
  <name xml:lang="nb">Filer</name>
  <name xml:lang="ms">Fail</name>
  <name xml:lang="mr">फाइल्स्</name>
  <name xml:lang="ml">ഫയലുകള്‍</name>
  <name xml:lang="mk">Датотеки</name>
  <name xml:lang="mjw">Files</name>
  <name xml:lang="lv">Datnes</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">Failai</name>
  <name xml:lang="ln">Ba Fisyé</name>
  <name xml:lang="ky">Файлдар</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">파일</name>
  <name xml:lang="kn">ಕಡತಗಳು</name>
  <name xml:lang="kk">Файлдар</name>
  <name xml:lang="kab">Ifuyla</name>
  <name xml:lang="ja">ファイル</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">File</name>
  <name xml:lang="is">Skrár</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Berkas</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">Fájlok</name>
  <name xml:lang="hr">Datoteke</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">फ़ाइल</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">קבצים</name>
  <name xml:lang="gu">ફાઇલો</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Ficheiros</name>
  <name xml:lang="gd">Faidhlichean</name>
  <name xml:lang="ga">Comhaid</name>
  <name xml:lang="fur">Files</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Fichiers</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Tiedostot</name>
  <name xml:lang="fa">پرونده‌ها</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Fitxategiak</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Failid</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Archivos</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Dosieroj</name>
  <name xml:lang="en_GB">Files</name>
  <name xml:lang="en_CA">Files</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Αρχεία</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Dateien</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">Filer</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Soubory</name>
  <name xml:lang="crh">Dosyeler</name>
  <name xml:lang="ckb">پەڕگەکان</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca@valencia">Fitxers</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Fitxers</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">Datoteke</name>
  <name xml:lang="bn_IN">ফাইল</name>
  <name xml:lang="bn">ফাইল</name>
  <name xml:lang="bg">Файлове</name>
  <name xml:lang="be">Файлы</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">Ficheros</name>
  <name xml:lang="as">ফাইলসমূহ</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">الملفات</name>
  <name xml:lang="an">Fichers</name>
  <name xml:lang="af">Lêers</name>
  <summary>Access and organize files</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_TW">存取與組織檔案</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_HK">存取與組織檔案</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">访问和组织文件</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="vi">Truy cập và tổ chức tập tin</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Доступ до файлів</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ug">ھۆججەتلەرنى تەشكىللەش ۋە زىيارەت</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Dosyalara eriş ve düzenle</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="th">เข้าถึงและจัดระเบียบแฟ้ม</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tg">Кушодан ва мураттабсозии файлҳо</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="te">దస్త్రాలను నిర్వహించండి మరియు ప్రాప్తించండి</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ta">கோப்புகளை அணுகு மற்றும் ஒழுங்கு படுத்து</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Kom åt och organisera filer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr@latin">Pristupite datotekama i organizujte ih</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr">Приступите датотекама и организујте их</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Dostop in razvrščanje datotek</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Pristupuje k súborom a organizuje ich</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Управление файлами</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Accesează și organizează fișiere</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Acesse e organize arquivos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Aceder e organizar ficheiros</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Otwieranie i organizowanie plików</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਫਾਇਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਤੇ ਪਰਬੰਧ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="or">ଫାଇଲମାନଙ୍କୁ ଅଭିଗମ କରନ୍ତୁ ଏବଂ ସଙ୍ଗଠନ କରନ୍ତୁ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="oc">Accedir als fichièrs e los organizar</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Aksesser og organiser filer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Bestanden gebruiken en organiseren</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ne">फाइलहरूको पहुँच र संगठन</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nb">Utforsk og organiser filer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ms">Capai dan urus fail</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="mr">फाइल्स्ला प्रवेश द्वया व संघटित करा</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ml">ഫയലുകള്‍ ലഭ്യമാക്കി ക്രമത്തിലാക്കുക</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="mk">Пристапувајте и организирајте датотеки</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lv">Piekļūt un organizēt datnes</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Atverti ir tvarkyti failus</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ln">Koyíngela mpe kobɔngisa ya kásá</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">파일 조작 및 정리</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="kn">ಕಡತಗಳನ್ನು ನಿಲುಕಿಸಿಕೊಳ್ಳಿ ಹಾಗು ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಿತವಾಗಿ ಜೋಡಿಸಿ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="kk">Файлдарға қатынау және оларды реттеу</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="kab">Kcem udiɣ suddes ifuyla</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ja">ファイルの操作や整理をします</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Accede ai file e li organizza</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="is">Aðgangur og skipulag skráa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Mengakses dan mengelola berkas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Fájlok elérése és rendszerezése</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hr">Pristupite i organizirajte datoteke</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hi">फ़ाइलों को व्यवस्थित और पहुँच प्राप्त करें</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">גישה לקבצים וארגונם</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gu">ફાઇલોને વાપરો અને સંચાલિત કરો</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Acceda e organice ficheiros</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gd">Faigh cothrom air faidhlichean is rianaich iad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ga">Déan rochtain ar chomhaid agus eagraigh iad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fur">Dopre e organize i files</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Accéder aux fichiers et les organiser</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Käsittele ja järjestä tiedostoja</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fa">دسترسی و سازماندهی پرونده‌ها</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Atzitu eta antolatu fitxategiak</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Ligipääs failidele ning failipuu korrastamine</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Acceder a archivos y organizarlos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Atingi kaj organizi dosierojn</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en_GB">Access and organise files</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en_CA">Access and organize files</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Προσπελάστε και οργανώστε αρχεία</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Auf Dateien zugreifen und diese organisieren</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="da">Tilgå og organisér filer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Přístup k souborům a jejich správa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="crh">Dosyelerge iriş ve olarnı tertiple</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ckb">چونەناو و ڕێکخستن</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca@valencia">Organitzeu i accediu a fitxers</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Organitzeu i accediu a fitxers</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Pristupite i organizujte datoteke</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bn_IN">ফাইলগুলি অ্যাক্সেস এবং সংগঠিত করুন</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bn">ফাইলে ব্যবাহর এবং সাজানো</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bg">Достъп и управление на файлове</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="be">Доступ і кіраванне файламі</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ast">Acceder a los ficheros y organizalos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="as">অভিগম কৰক আৰু ফাইলসমূহ আয়োজিত কৰক</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">نظم الملفات وصِل إليها</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="an">Accedir a os fichers y organizar-los</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="af">Besoek/Deurblaai en organiseer lêers</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Files, also known as Nautilus, is the default file manager of the GNOME desktop.
      It provides a  simple and integrated way of managing your files and browsing your file system.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">《檔案》，亦稱為 Nautilus，是 GNOME 桌面的預設檔案管理員。它提供了簡易與整合的方法讓您管理與瀏覽檔案系統。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">文件，又名“Nautilus”，是 GNOME 桌面环境的默认文件管理器。它提供简单集成的方式来管理文件和浏览文件系统。</p>
    <p xml:lang="vi">Tập tin, được biết đến là Nautilus, là ứng dụng quản lý tập tin mặc định cho môi trường máy tính để bàn GNOME. Nó đơn giản và thích hợp cho quản lý và duyệt tập tin trên hệ thống của bạn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Файли, також відомі як Nautilus, — типовий файловий менеджер для стільничного середовища GNOME. Він дозволяє простий та інтегрований спосіб упорядкування ваших файлів і переглядання файлової системи.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Nautilus olarak da bilinen Dosyalar, GNOME masaüstünün ön tanımlı dosya yöneticisidir. Kolay ve tümleşik biçimde dosyalarınızı yönetmenizi ve dosya sisteminizde gezinmenizi sağlar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Filer, också känd som Nautilus, är standardfilhanteraren för GNOME-skrivbordet. Den tillhandahåller ett enkelt och integrerat sätt att hantera dina filer samt bläddra i ditt filsystem.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">Датотеке, такође познате и као Наутилус, је подразумевани управник датотека Гномове радне површи. Обезбеђује једноставан и обједињени начин за управљање вашим датотекама и за разгледање вашег система датотека.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Program Nautilus, znan tudi z imenom Datoteke, je privzeti upravljalnik datotek za namizje GNOME. Enostaven vmesnik in široka povezanost programnika omogoča brskanje in upravljanje datotek tudi znotraj različnih programov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Aplikácia Súbory, tiež známa ako Nautilus, je predvolený správca súborov prostredia GNOME. Poskytuje jednoduchý a integrovaný spôsob spravovania vašich súborov a prehliadania vášho systému súborov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Файлы — файловый менеджер по умолчанию для рабочего стола GNOME, также известный как приложение «Nautilus». Предоставляет простой способ для управления файлами и навигации по файловой системе.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Nautilus, cunoscut și ca Fișiere, este administratorul de fișiere implicit al mediului desktop GNOME. Furnizează o modalitate simplă și integrată de a vă administra fișierele și de a naviga prin sistemul de fișiere.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">Arquivos, também conhecido como Nautilus, é o gerenciador de arquivos padrão do ambiente GNOME. Ele oferece uma maneira simples e integrada de gerenciar seus arquivos e de navegar pelo sistema de arquivos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Ficheiros, também conhecido por Nautilus, é o gestor de ficheiros predefinido do ambiente de trabalho GNOME. Este fornece uma forma simples e integrada de gerir os seus ficheiros e de navegar no seu sistema.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Menedżer plików, znany także jako Nautilus, jest domyślnym menedżerem plików dla środowiska GNOME. Dostarcza on prosty i zintegrowany sposób na zarządzanie plikami i przeglądanie systemu plików.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਫਾਇਲਜ਼ (Files), ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਟੀਲਸ ਵੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਗਨੋਮ ਡੈਸਕਟਾਪ ਲਈ ਡਿਫਾਲਟ ਫਾਇਲ ਮੈਨੇਜਰ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਤੁਹਾਡੀਆਂ ਫਾਇਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਅਤੇ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਫਾਇਲ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਦੀ ਝਲਕ ਵੇਖਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਸਧਾਰਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਂਝਾ ਢੰਗ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="oc">Fichièrs, tanben conegut jol nom de Nautilus, es lo gestionari de fichièrs per defaut del burèu GNOME. Ofrís un mejan simple e integrat de gerir vòstres fichièrs e navigar dins vòstre sistèma de fichièrs.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Bestanden, ook bekend onder de naam Nautilus, is het standaard bestandsbeheerprogramma voor de Gnome-werkomgeving. Op een eenvoudige en geïntegreerde wijze kunt u hiermee uw bestanden beheren en uw bestandssysteem verkennen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ne">नटिलस, उर्फ फाइल, जिनोम डेस्क्टपको पूर्वनिर्धारित फाइल प्रबन्धक हो । यसले तपाईँको फाइल व्यवस्थापन गर्न र आफ्नो फाइलहरू खोज्न एक सरल र एकीकृत तरिका प्रदान गर्छ।.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nb">Filer, også kjent som Nautilus, er forvalgt filbehandler for GNOME-skrivebordet. Det gir deg en enkel og integrert måte å håndtere filer og filsystemet på.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ms">Fail, juga dikenali sebagai Nautilus, merupakan pengurus fail lalai untuk atas meja GNOME. Ia menawarkan cara mengurus fail dan melayari sistem fail yang mudah dan bersepadu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lv">Datnes, zināms arī kā “Nautilus” ir GNOME darbvirsmas noklusējuma datņu pārvaldnieks. Tas sniedz vienkāršu un integrētu datņu pārvaldības un datņu sistēmas pārlūkošanas veidu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Failai, dar žinoma kaip Nautilus, yra numatytoji GNOME darbalaukio failų tvarkytuvė. Ji suteikia paprastą ir integruotą būdą failų tvarkymui ir failų sistemos naršymui.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">파일(노틸러스라고도 함)은 그놈 데스크톱의 기본 파일 관리 프로그램입니다. 이 프로그램을 이용해 간단하고 통합된 방식으로 파일을 관리하고 파일 시스템을 찾아 볼 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kk">Файлдар (сонымен қатар Nautilus ретінде белгілі) - бұл GNOME жұмыс үстелі үшін негізгі файлдық басқарушысы. Ол файлдарды басқару және жүйені шолудың қарапайым және интеграцияланған жолын ұсынады.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">ファイル (Nautilus という名称でも知られています) は、GNOME デスクトップで使用されているデフォルトのファイルマネージャーです。ファイルの管理やファイルシステムの閲覧をシンプルかつ統合的に行うことができます。</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">File, noto anche come «Nautilus», è il gestore di file predefinito dell'ambiente grafico GNOME. Fornisce gestione dei file ed esplorazione del file system semplici e integrate.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">Skráastjóri, einnig þekktur sem Nautilusi, er sjálfgefinn skráastjóri GNOME skjáborðsumhverfisins. Þetta er einföld og samtvinnuð leið til að sýsla með skrár og til að vafra um á skráakerfinu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Berkas, yang juga dikenal sebagai Nautilus, adalah manajer berkas bawaan dari destop GNOME. Ini menyediakan cara terintegrasi dan sederhana untuk pengelolaan berkas-berkas Anda dan meramban sistem berkas Anda.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">A Fájlok, más néven Nautilus a GNOME asztali környezet alapértelmezett fájlkezelője. Egyszerű és integrált lehetőségeket nyújt a fájlok kezeléséhez és fájlrendszere tallózásához.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hr">Datoteke, isto tako poznat i kao Nautilus, je uobičajeni upravitelj datoteka za GNOME radno okruženje. Pruža jednostavan i integriran način upravljanja s vašim datotekama i pregledavanje vašeg datotečnog sustava.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">‏קבצים, ידוע גם כ־Nautilus, הוא מנהל הקבצים כבררת מחדל עבור שולחן העבודה GNOME. הוא מספק דרך פשוטה ומשולבת לניהול הקבצים שלך ולעיון במערכת הקבצים שלך.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Nautilus, tamén coñecido como Ficheiros, é o xestor de ficheiros por omisión do escritorio GNOME. Fornece unha forma simple e integrada de xestionar os seus ficheiros e explorar o seu sistema de ficheiros.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fur">Files, cognossût ancje come Nautilus, al è il gjestôr di file predefinît dal ambient grafic GNOME. Al furnìs une semplice e integrade maniere di ministrâ i tiei files e esplorâ il to file-system.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fichiers, également connu sous le nom de Nautilus, est le gestionnaire de fichiers par défaut du bureau GNOME. Il offre un moyen simple et intégré de gérer vos fichiers et naviguer dans votre système de fichiers.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Tiedostot, joka tunnetaan myös nimellä Nautilus, on Gnome-työpöydän tiedostonhallinnan oletussovellus. Sen avulla tiedostojen selailu ja hallinta on vaivatonta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fa">پرونده‌ها که به نام ناتیلوس نیز شناخته می‌شود، مدیر پروندهٔ پیش‌گزیده میزکار گنوم است. این برنامه راهی ساده و یک‌پارچه برای مدیریت پرونده‌ها و مرور سامانه‌پرونده‌هایتان فراهم می‌کند.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Fitxategiak aplikazioa, Nautilus izenarekin ere ezaguna dena, GNOME mahaigainaren fitxategi-kudeatzaile lehenetsia da. Zure fitxategiak kudeatzeko eta baita fitxategi-sistema arakatzeko modu bateratua eta xumea eskaintzen du.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Archivos, también conocido como Nautilus, es el gestor de archivos predeterminado del escritorio GNOME. Proporciona una manera sencilla e integrada para gestionar sus archivos y explorar el sistema de archivos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Dosieroj, ankaŭ konata kiel Naŭtilo, estas la implicita dosieradministrilo de GNOME. Ĝi disponigas simplan kaj integritan manieron de administrado de viaj dosieroj kaj foliumado de via dosiersistemo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en_GB">Files, also known as Nautilus, is the default file manager of the GNOME desktop. It provides a simple and integrated way of managing your files and browsing your file system.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Ο Ναυτίλος, γνωστός και ως Αρχεία, είναι ο προεπιλεγμένος διαχειριστής αρχείων του GNOME. Προσφέρει έναν απλό και ολοκληρωμένο τρόπο διαχείρισης των αρχείων και περιήγησης του συστήματος αρχείων.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Dateien, auch bekannt als Nautilus, ist die mitgelieferte Dateiverwaltung der GNOME Arbeitsumgebung. Es bietet eine einfache und maßgeschneiderte Art Ihre Dateien zu verwalten und Ihr Dateisystem zu durchsuchen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">Programmet Filer, også kendt som Nautilus, er standardfilhåndteringen for GNOME-skrivebordet. Nautilus tilbyder en simpel og integreret måde at gennemse filsystemet på og filhåndtering generelt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Aplikace Soubory, známá i pod názvem Nautilus, je výchozí správce souborů pro uživatelské prostředí GNOME. Poskytuje jednoduchou a dobře začleněnou správu vašich souborů a procházení vaším souborovým systémem.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ckb">پەڕگەکان، هەروەها بە ناوی ناوتیلەس بەناوبانگە، بریتیە لە نەرمەکاڵای بنەڕەتی بۆ بەڕێوەبردنی پەڕگە لە گنۆم. شیوازێکی سادە و گونجێنراو و تایبەتمەندی زۆر دابین دەکات بۆ ڕێکخستن و گەڕان بەناو پەڕگەکانی سیستمەکەت.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Fitxers, també conegut com el Nautilus, és el gestor de fitxers per defecte de l'escriptori GNOME. Permet, d'una forma simple i integrada, la gestió de fitxers i la navegació pel sistema de fitxers.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bn_IN">নটিলাস নামে পরিচিত ফাইলস হ'ল জিনোম ডেস্কটপের ডিফল্ট ফাইল ম্যানেজার। এটি আপনার ফাইলগুলি পরিচালনা করার এবং আপনার ফাইল সিস্টেমটি ব্রাউজ করার একটি সহজ এবং সংহত পদ্ধতি সরবরাহ করে।</p>
    <p xml:lang="bg">„Файлове“, известно още като Наутилус (Nautilus) е стандартният мениджър на файлове в работната среда GNOME. Той предоставя лесен и интегриран в средата начин за управление на файловете и преглед на файловата система.</p>
    <p xml:lang="be">Файлы — прадвызначаны кіраўнік файлаў для асяроддзя GNOME, які таксама вядомы як Наўтылус. Ён прадастаўляе просты і зручны спосаб кіравання файламі і файлавымі сістэмамі.</p>
    <p>
      Nautilus supports all the basic functions of a file manager and more.
      It can search and manage your files and folders, both locally and on a network,
      read and write data to and from removable media, run scripts, and launch applications.
      It has three views: Icon Grid, Icon List, and Tree List.
      Its functions can be extended with plugins and scripts.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">Nautilus 支援檔案管理的所有基礎功能，甚至更多。它可以搜尋與管理您的檔案與資料夾，無論是本地端或是網路；讀寫可移除媒體的資料、執行命令稿與應用程式。它有三種檢視：圖示格線、圖示清單和樹狀清單。它的功能可以透過外掛程式與命令稿擴充。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_HK">Nautilus 支援檔案管理的所有基礎功能，甚至更多。它可以搜尋與管理你的檔案與資料夾，無論是本地端或是網絡；讀寫可移除媒體的資料、執行命令稿與應用程式。它有三種檢視：圖示格線、圖示清單和樹狀清單。它的功能可以透過外掛程式與命令稿擴充。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">“文件”不仅提供所有基本的文件管理功能，还支持搜索和管理本地和远程网络上的文件及文件夹，读写可移动存储上的数据，运行脚本和启动程序。它有三种视图：图标网格、图标列表、树列表。可以用插件和脚本扩展它的功能。</p>
    <p xml:lang="vi">Nautilus hỗ trợ các tính năng cơ bản về quản lý tập tin và hơn thế nữa. Nó có thể tìm kiếm và quản lý các tập tin và thư mục của bạn, cả trên máy nội bộ và cả trên mạng, đọc và ghi dữ liệu từ và đến từ đĩa đa phương tiện, chạy văn lệnh, và khởi chạy các ứng dụng. Nó có ba cách trình bày: Dạng lưới biểu tượng, Danh sách biểu tượng, và cây. Các tính năng của nó có thể được mở rộng bằng các phần bổ xung và văn lệnh.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Nautilus підтримує всі базові можливості файлового менеджера і навіть більше. Він може шукати і впорядковувати ваші файли і теки як локально, так і в мережі, читати і записувати дані через змінний носій, запускати скрипти і запускати програми. Він має три режими перегляду: ґратки піктограм, список піктограм, ієрархічний список. Можливості можна розширити за допомогою додатків і скриптів.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Nautilus, bir dosya yöneticisindeki tüm temel işlevleri ve daha çoğunu bulundurur. Hem bilgisayarınızdaki hem de ağdaki dosyalarınızı ve klasörlerinizi tarayabilir, çıkarılabilir ortamlara veri yazabilir ve okuyabilir, betik ve uygulamaları çalıştırabilir. Üç tür görünümü bulunur: Simge, Liste ve Ağaç. Nautilus’un işlevleri eklentiler ve betiklerle genişletilebilir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="th">Nautilus รองรับการทำงานพื้นฐานทุกอย่างของเครื่องมือจัดการแฟ้มและมากกว่านั้น สามารถค้นหาและจัดการแฟ้มและโฟลเดอร์ของคุณ ทั้งในเครื่องและในเครือข่าย อ่านและเขียนข้อมูลกับสื่อถอดเสียบ เรียกทำงานสคริปต์ และเรียกทำงานโปรแกรม Nautilus มี 3 มุมมองให้เลือกใช้: แถวตารางไอคอน, รายชื่อไอคอน และแบบต้นไม้ การทำงานต่างๆ สามารถขยายต่อเติมได้โดยใช้ปลั๊กอินและสคริปต์</p>
    <p xml:lang="te">నాటిలస్ ఫైల్ నిర్వాహిక యొక్క ప్రాధమిక ఫంక్షన్లను అందించును. ఇది మీ స్థానిక మరియు నెట్వర్క్ స్థానములనందలి ఫైళ్ళను వెతుక గలదు నిర్వహించగలదు, తీసిపెట్టగల మాధ్యమానికి డాటా వ్రాయగలదు నుండి చదువగలదు, స్క్రిప్ట్స్ నడుపగలదు, అనువర్తనాలను దించగలదు. అది ముడు దర్శనాలను కలిగివుంటుంది: ప్రతిమ జాబితా, ప్రతిమ గ్రిడ్, మరియు ట్రీ జాబితా. దీని ఫంక్షన్లు చొప్పింతలతో మరియు స్క్రిప్టులతో విస్తరింపచేయవచ్చు.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ta">Nautilus பயன்பாடு ஒரு கோப்பு நிர்வாகி வழங்கும் அனைத்து அடிப்படை செயலம்சங்களையும், இன்னும் சில கூடுதல் அம்சங்களையும் வழங்குகிறது. கணினிக்குள்ளும் பிணையத்திலும் இருக்கும் கோப்புகளையும் கோப்புறைகளையும் தேடவும் நிர்வகிக்கவும் பயன்படுகிறது, நீக்கத்தக்க ஊடகங்களில் இருந்து தரவை வாசிக்கவும் அவற்றில் தரவை எழுதவும் பயன்படுகிறது, ஸ்கிரிப்ட்டுகளை இயக்க மற்றும் பயன்பாடுகளைத் துவக்க பயன்படுகிறது. இதில் சின்ன வலையமைப்பு, சின்னப் பட்டியல் மற்றும் கிளையமைப்புப் பட்டியல் என மூன்று காட்சிகள் உள்ளன. செருகுநிரல்களையும் ஸ்கிரிப்ட்டுகளையும் பயன்படுத்தி இதன் அம்சங்களை இன்னும் விரிவாக்கலாம்.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Nautilus stöder en filhanterares alla grundläggande funktioner och mer därtill. Den kan söka och hantera din filer och mappar, både lokalt och på ett nätverk, läsa och skapa data till och från utbytbar media, köra skript, och starta program. Den har tre vyer: Ikonrutnät, ikonlista, och trädlista. Dess funktioner kan utökas med insticksmoduler och skript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr@latin">Nautilus podržava sve osnovne funkcije upravnika datoteka i još po nešto. Može da pretražuje i upravlja vašim datotekama i fasciklama, kako u mestu tako i na mreži, da čita i piše podatke na i sa uklonjivih medijuma, da izvršava skripte, i da pokreće programe. Poseduje tri pregleda: mrežu ikonica, spisak ikonica i pregled u stablu. Njegove funkcije mogu biti proširene priključcima i skriptama.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">Наутилус подржава све основне функције управника датотека и још по нешто. Може да претражује и управља вашим датотекама и фасциклама, како у месту тако и на мрежи, да чита и пише податке на и са уклоњивих медијума, да извршава скрипте, и да покреће програме. Поседује три прегледа: мрежу иконица, списак иконица и преглед у стаблу. Његове функције могу бити проширене прикључцима и скриптама.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Program Nautilus podpira vse osnovne funkcije upravljalnika datotek in še mnogo več. Omogoča iskanje in urejanje datotek in map krajevno in v omrežju, branje in pisanje podatkov na odstranljive nosilce, zagon skriptov in programov. Podpira tri poglede; ikonski, seznamski in drevesni. Vse funkcije je mogoče razširiti s vstavki in skripti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Program Nautilus podporuje všetky základné funkcie správcu súborov a ešte viac. Dokáže vyhľadať a spravovať vaše súbory a priečinky, miestne aj v sieti, čítať a zapísať údaje na vymeniteľných médiách, spustiť skripty a aplikácie. Obsahuje tri druhy zobrazení: Mriežka ikôn, zoznam ikôn a stromové zobrazenie. Jeho funkcie môžu byť rozšírené pomocou zásuvných modulov a skriptov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Nautilus поддерживает все базовые функции файловых менеджеров. С помощью Nautilus можно управлять файлами и папками, выполнять поиск файлов и папок как локально, так и по сети, читать и записывать данные на съёмные устройства, выполнять сценарии и запускать приложения. Nautilus предлагает три режима просмотра: сетка из значков, список из значков и древовидный список. Функциональность Nautilus можно расширять с помощью модулей и сценариев.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Nautilus suportă toate funcțiile de bază ale unui administrator de fișiere și chiar mai mult. Poate căuta și administra fișiere și dosare, atât local cât și într-o rețea, poate citi și scrie date de pe și către medii de stocare detașabile, rula scripturi, și lansa aplicații. Vine cu trei moduri de vizualizare: grilă de iconițe, listă de iconițe și listă arborescentă. Funcționalitatea sa poate fi extinsă cu ajutorul modulelor și a scripturilor.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">O Nautilus possui suporte a todas as funções básicas de um gerenciador de arquivos e muitas mais. Ele pode pesquisar e gerenciar seus arquivos e pastas, tanto localmente quanto em uma rede, ler e gravar dados de e para mídias removíveis, executar scripts e executar aplicativos. O mesmo possui três visões: grade de ícones, lista de ícones e lista em árvore. E as funções dele podem ser estendidas com plug-ins e scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Nautilus suporta todas as funções básicas de um gestor de ficheiros e mais algumas. Pode procurar e gerir os seus ficheiros e pastas, quer localmente, quer numa rede, ler e escrever dados de e para unidades removíveis, executar scripts e iniciar aplicações. Tem três vistas: Grelha de ícones, Lista de ícones e Lista em árvore. As suas funções podem sem alargadas com extensões e scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Program Nautilus obsługuje wszystkie podstawowe funkcje menedżera plików, a także wiele więcej. Może wyszukiwać i zarządzać plikami i katalogami, zarówno lokalnie, jak i w sieci, odczytywać i zapisywać dane na i z nośników wymiennych, wykonywać skrypty i uruchamiać programy. Ma on trzy widoki: siatkę ikon, listę ikon i listę w formie drzewa. Jego funkcje mogą być rozszerzane za pomocą wtyczek i skryptów.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਨਟੀਲਸ ਫਾਇਲ ਮੈਨੇਜਰ ਲਈ ਸਭ ਮੁੱਢਲੀਆਂ ਸਹੂਲਤ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਤੁਹਾਡੀਆਂ ਫਾਇਲਾਂ ਤੇ ਫੋਲਡਰਾਂ ਲਈ ਲੋਕਲ ਅਤੇ ਨੈੱਟਵਰਕ, ਦੋਵਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਲੱਭਣ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਲਈ, ਹਟਾਉਣਯੋਗ ਮੀਡਿਆ ਉੱਤੇ ਡਾਟਾ ਲਿਖਣ ਤੇ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ, ਸਕ੍ਰਿਪਟਾਂ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਅਤੇ ਐਪਲੀਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਮੱਦਦ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਿੰਨ ਝਲਕਾਂ ਹਨ: ਆਈਕਾਨ ਗਰਿੱਡ, ਆਈਕਾਨ ਸੂਚੀ, ਅਤੇ ਟਰੀ ਸੂਚੀ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਲੱਗਇਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਕ੍ਰਿਪਟਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਧਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="or">Nautilus ଫାଇଲ ପରିଚାଳନା ଏବଂ ଅନ୍ୟାନ୍ୟ ସମସ୍ତ ମୌଳିକ କାର୍ଯ୍ଯଗୁଡ଼ିକୁ ସହାୟତା କରିଥାଏ। ଏହା ଆପଣଙ୍କର ଫାଇଲ ଏବଂ ଫୋଲଡରଗୁଡ଼ିକୁ ସନ୍ଧାନ ଏବଂ ପରିଚାଳନା କରିପାରିବ, ଉଭୟ ସ୍ଥାନୀୟ ଭାବରେ ଏବଂ ନେଟୱର୍କ ଉପରେ, କଢ଼ାଯୋଗ୍ଯ ମେଡିଆରେ ତଥ୍ୟ ପଢ଼ିପାରିବଏବଂ ଲେଖିପାରିବ, ସ୍କ୍ରିପ୍ଟ ଚଲାଇ ପାରିବ, ଏବଂପ୍ରୟୋଗଗୁଡ଼ିକୁ ଆରମ୍ଭ କରିପାରିବ। ଏଥିରେ ତିନୋଟି ଦୃଶ୍ୟ ଅଛି: ଚିତ୍ର ସଂକେତ ଗ୍ରୀଡ, ଏବଂ ଟ୍ରୀ ତାଲିକା। ଏହାରକାର୍ଯ୍ୟଗୁଡ଼ିକୁ ପ୍ଲଗଇନ ଏବଂ ସ୍କ୍ରିପ୍ଟଗୁଡ଼ିକ ସହିତ ବିସ୍ତାର କରାଯାଇପାରିବ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="oc">Nautilus ofrís totas las foncionalitats basicas e avançadas d'un gestionari de fichièrs. Pòt recercar e gerir vòstres fichièrs e dorsièrs, locals o sus una ret, legir e escriure de donadas cap a de mèdias amovibles, executar d'escripts e d'aplicacions. Presenta tres vistas : grasilha d'icònas, lista d'icònas, e lista arborescenta. Sas foncionalitats pòdon èsser espandidas amb d'empeutons e d'escripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Nautilus ondersteunt alle basisfuncties van een bestandsbeheerprogramma en meer. U kunt uw bestanden en mappen doorzoeken en beheren, zowel lokaal als op een netwerk, gegevens lezen van en schrijven naar verwijderbare media, scripts uitvoeren, en toepassingen starten. Er zijn drie vormen van weergave: pictogrammenraster, pictogrammenlijst en boomstructuurlijst. De functies kunnen worden uitgebreid via plug-ins en scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ne">नौटीलस फाइल प्रबन्धकको सम्पुण आधारभूत कार्य समर्थन गर्दछ। यो तपाईँको  फाइल र फोल्डरहरू, स्थानीय रुपमा वा संजालमा, खोज तथा व्यवस्थापन गर्न, हटाउन सकिने संचार साधनबाट तथ्यांक पढ्न र लेख्न, कार्यक्रम तथा लिपी प्रक्षेपण गर्न सक्छ। यसको तीनवटा रुप छ: चिन्ह ढांचा, चिन्ह सूची र तहगत सूची। यसको कार्य प्लगइन र लिपि संग विस्तार गर्न सकिन्छ।.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nb">Nautilus støtter alle grunnleggende funksjoner i en filbehandler og mer. Den kan finne og håndtere filer og mapper, både lokalt og på nettverket, lese og skrive data fra eksterne medier samt kjøre skript og starte programmer. Den har tre visninger: Ikonrutenett, ikonliste og treliste. Funksjonaliteten kan utvides med tillegg og skript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ms">Nautilus menyokong semua fungsi asas pengurus fail dan banyak lagi. Ia boleh mencari dan menguruskan fail dan folder anda, kedua-duanya secara setempat dan rangkaian, membaca dan menulis data ke dan dari media boleh tanggal, menjalankan skrip, dan melancarkan aplikasi. Ia mempunyai tiga pandangan: Ikon Grid, Icon Senarai dan Senarai Pohon. Fungsinya boleh dilanjutkan dengan pemalam dan skrip.</p>
    <p xml:lang="mr">नॉटिलस फाइल व्यवस्थापकाच्या सर्व मूळ कार्यपद्धती आणि अधिककरिता समर्थन पुरवते. ते फाइल्स आणि फोल्डर्स शोधते आणि व्यवस्थापीत करते, दोन्ही स्थानीयरित्या आणि नेटवर्कवरील, काढून टाकण्याजोगी मिडीयापासून डाटा वाचते आणि लिहते, स्क्रिप्ट्स चालवते, आणि ॲप्लिकेशन्स सुरू करते. त्याचे तीन अवलोकन आहेत: चिन्ह ग्रीड, चिन्ह सूची, आणि वृक्ष सूची. प्लगइन्स आणि स्क्रिप्ट्ससह फंकशन्स विस्तारित करणे शक्य आहे.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lv">Nautilus atbalsta arī visas pamata datņu pārvaldnieka funkcijas un vēl vairāk. Tas var meklēt un pārvaldīt datnes un mapes, gan lokāli, gan tīklā, lasīt un rakstīt datnes noņemamos datu nesējos, izpildīt skriptus un palaist lietotnes. Tam ir trīs skati — ikonu režģis, ikonu saraksts un koka saraksts. Tā funkcionalitāti var paplašināt ar spraudņiem un skriptiem.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Nautilus palaiko visas pagrindines failų tvarkytuvės funkcijas ir daugiau. Galima ieškoti bei tvarkyti failus ir aplankus, tiek vietoje, tiek tinkle, skaityti ir rašyti duomenis į išimamas laikmenas, vykdyti scenarijus bei paleisti programas. Yra trys vaizdai: piktogramų tinklelis, piktogramų sąrašas bei medžio sąrašas. Funkcijas galima praplėsti įskiepiais ir scenarijais.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ln">Nautilus ezo salisa lolenge mpe motindo nini yako monisa, kobatela mpe kosala nyonso oyo olingi na ba fisyé. Ekoki kolukisa mpe kotambwisa ba fisyé na ba dosyé,na rézo to mpe na masini, kotanga mpe kobomba biloko na ba disiki,kopelisa mpe kotambwisa ba esaliseli.Ezali na lolenge ya kotalisa misato:griyaze ya Ikone, Ikone lolenge ya lístɛ, na lístɛ ya moété. Makoki mosusu ekoki kobakisama na botie plugin to ba skripte.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">노틸러스는 파일 관리 프로그램의 모든 기본 기능을 지원하고 더 많은 기능이 있습니다. 노틸러스에서 로컬이든 원격 모두에 있는 파일과 폴더를 검색하고 관리할 수 있고, 이동식 미디어에서 데이터를 읽고 쓸 수 있고, 스크립트와 응용 프로그램을 실행할 수 있습니다. 노틸러스는 세 가지 종류의 보기 모드가 있습니다. 아이콘 격자, 아이콘 목록, 계층 구조 목록입니다. 노틸러스의 기능은 플러그인과 스크립트를 이용해 확장할 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kn">Nautilus ಒಂದು ಕಡತ ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಾಪಕದ ಎಲ್ಲಾ ಮೂಲಭೂತ ಕಾರ್ಯಭಾರಗಳನ್ನು ಮತ್ತು ಇನ್ನೂ ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನವುಗಳನ್ನು ಒದಗಿಸುತ್ತದೆ. ಇದು ನಿಮ್ಮ ಕಡತಗಳನ್ನು ಮತ್ತು ಕಡತಕೋಶಗಳನ್ನು ಸ್ಥಳೀಯವಾಗಿ ಮತ್ತು ಒಂದು ಜಾಲಬಂಧದಲ್ಲಿ ಹುಡುಕಲು ಮತ್ತು ವ್ಯವಸ್ಥಾಪಿಸಲು, ತೆಗೆಯಬಹುದಾದ ಮಾಧ್ಯಮಕ್ಕೆ ಮತ್ತು ಮಾಧ್ಯಮದಿಂದ ಮಾಹಿತಿಯನ್ನು ಓದಲು ಮತ್ತು ಬರೆಯಲು, ಸ್ಕ್ರಿಪ್ಟ್‌ಗಳನ್ನು ಚಲಾಯಿಸಲು, ಮತ್ತು ಅನ್ವಯಗಳನ್ನು ಆರಂಭಿಸಲು ಶಕ್ತವಾಗಿರುತ್ತದೆ. ಇದು ಮೂರು ಬಗೆಯ ನೋಟಗಳನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿರುತ್ತದೆ: ಚಿಹ್ನೆ ಚೌಕಜಾಲ, ಚಿಹ್ನೆ ಪಟ್ಟಿ, ಮತ್ತು ವೃಕ್ಷ ಪಟ್ಟಿ. ಪ್ಲಗ್‌ಇನ್‌ಗಳು ಮತ್ತು ಸ್ಕ್ರಿಪ್ಟ್‌ಗಳನ್ನು ಬಳಸಿಕೊಂಡು ಇದರ ಕ್ರಿಯೆಗಳನ್ನು ವಿಸ್ತರಿಸಬಹುದು.</p>
    <p xml:lang="kk">Nautilus файлдар басқарушысының барлық қарапайым, және одан да көп мүмкіндіктерін қолдайды. Ол жергілікті және желідегі файлдар және бумаларды іздеп, оларды басқара алады, ауыстырмалы тасушылардан және оларға жазып, оқи алады, скрипттерді және қолданбаларды жөнелте алады. Оның үш көрінісі бар: таңбашалар торы, таңбашалар тізімі және ағаш тектес тізім. Оның мүмкіндіктерін плагиндер және скрипттермен кеңейтуге болады.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">Nautilus は、ファイルマネージャーとしての基本機能を完備するだけでなく、便利な機能もたくさんあります。たとえば、ファイルとフォルダーの検索と管理、ローカルおよびネットワーク上でのファイル操作、リムーバルメディアのデータ読み書き、スクリプトの実行アプリケーションの起動などです。三種類の表示モードが利用できます: アイコングリッド、アイコンリスト、そしてツリーリストです。プラグインとスクリプトを利用して機能拡張ができます。</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Supporta tutte le funzionalità di base di un gestore di file e molto altro: è in grado di eseguire ricerche e gestire file e cartelle (localmente e da remoto), leggere e scrivere da supporti rimovibili, eseguire script e lanciare applicazioni. Dispone di tre diverse tipologie di visualizzazione: come una griglia d'icone, un elenco d'icone e un elenco ad albero. È possibile estenderne le funzionalità attraverso plugin e script.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">Nautilus styður allar helstu aðgerðir við umsýslu skráa, og fleira til. Hann getur leitað að og meðhöndlað skrár og möppur, bæði á tölvunni sjálfri sem og á netkerfum. Hann getur lesið og skrifað gögn á útskiptanlegum gagnamiðlum, keyrt skriftur og keyrt forrit. Hann er með þrenns konar ásýnd: uppraðaðar táknmyndir, táknmyndir í lista og greinalistasýn. Hægt er að bæta við eiginleika með hjálparforritum (plugins) og með skriftum.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Nautilus mendukung semua fungsi dasar dari suatu manajer berkas dan lebih. Ini dapat mencari dan mengelola berkas dan folder Anda, lokal dan pada jaringan, membaca dan menulis data ke dan dari media lepas pasang, menjalankan skrip, dan meluncurkan aplikasi. Ini memiilki tiga tilikan, Kisi Ikon, Daftar Ikon, dan Daftar Pohon. Fungsinya bisa diperluas dengan pengaya dan skrip.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">A Nautilus támogatja a fájlkezelők alapvető funkcióit és még sok mást is. Képes fájlok és mappák keresésére és kezelésére helyileg és a hálózaton egyaránt, adatokat olvasni és írni cserélhető adathordozókra, parancsfájlokat futtatni és alkalmazásokat elindítani. Három nézete van: ikonrács, ikonlista és falista. Funkcionalitása bővítményekkel és parancsfájlokkal bővíthető.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hr">Nautilus podržava sve osnovne funkcije upravitelja datotekama i još mnogo toga. Može pretraživati i upravljati vašim datotekama i mapama, lokalno i putem mreže, čitati i pisati podatke na i s uklonjivih medija, pokretati skripte i aplikacije. Ima tri pogleda: pogled ikona, pogled popisa i pogled stabla. Njegove funkcije mogu se proširiti priključcima i skriptama.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">नॉटिलस फ़ाइल प्रबंधक और कुछ अन्य चीजों का बेसिक कार्य का समर्थन करता है. यह आपकी फ़ाइल और फोल्डर को खोज और प्रबंधित कर सकता है, दोनों स्थानीय रूप से और संजाल पर, विस्थापनीय मीडिया से डाटा लिख और पढ़ सकता है, स्क्रिप्ट लिख सकता है, और अनुप्रयोग लॉन्च कर सकता है. इसके तीन दृश्य हैं: Icon Grid, Icon List, और Tree List. इसके कार्य प्लगिन और स्क्रिप्ट से विस्तारित किए जा सकते हैं.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">‏Nautilus תומך בכל הפעולות הבסיסיות של מנהל קבצים ויותר. הוא יכול לחפש ולנהל את הקבצים והתיקיות שלך, מקומיים ועל הרשת, לקרוא ולכתוב מידע אל וממדיות מרוחקות, להריץ תסריטים ולשגר יישומים. יש לו שלוש תצוגות: רשת סמלים, רשימת סמלים ורשימת עץ. ניתן להרחיב את הפעולות שלו עם תוספים ותסריטים.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gu">Nautilus એ ફાઇલ સંચાલક અને વધુની બધા મૂળભૂત વિધેયોને આધાર આપે છે. તે તમારી ફાઇલો અને ફોલ્ડરોને શોધી અને સંચાલિત કરી શકાય છે, બંને સ્થાનિક રીતે અને નેટવર્ક પર, દૂર કરી શકાય તેવી મીડિયામાંથી અને તેમાં માહિતીને વાંચો અને લખો, સ્ક્રિપ્ટને ચલાવો, અને કાર્યક્રમોને શરૂ કરો. તેની પાસે ત્રણ દૃશ્ય છે: ચિહ્ન જાળી, ચિહ્ન યાદી, અને ટ્રી યાદી. તેનાં વિધેયો પ્લગઇન અને સ્ક્રીપ્ટ સાથે વિસ્તારી શકાય છે.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Nautilus admite todas as funcións básicas de xestión de ficheiros e máis. Pode buscar e xestionar todos os seus ficheiros e cartafoles, tanto locais como nunha rede, lee e escribe datos nos soportes multimedia, executa scripts e inicia aplicacións. Conta con tres vistas: Grella de iconas, Lista de iconas e Lista en árbore. As súas funcións poden estenderse con engadidos e scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gd">Bheir Nautilus taic do na h-uile foincsean bunasach aig manaidsear fhaidhlichean ’s a bharrachd. Tha e comasach air lorg sna faidhlichean agus pasganan agad ’s an stiùireadh, an dà chuid gu ionadail ’s air lìonra, air dàta a leughadh ’s a sgrìobhadh gu uidheaman so-ghiùlain, air sgriobtaichean a ruith agus air prògraman a thòiseachadh. Tha trì seallaidhean ri fhaighinn: griod de dh’ìomhaigheagan, liosta no craobh. Gabhaidh na feartan a leudachadh le plugain ’s sgriobtaichean.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fur">Nautilus al supuarte dutis lis funzions basilârs di un gjestôr di file e alc di plui. Al pues cirî e ministrâ i tiei files e cartelis, ducj e doi locâi e suntune rêt, lei e scrivi dâts viers e di dispositîfs estraibii, eseguî script e fâ partî aplicazions. Al à trê viodudis: Gridele di iconis, liste di iconis e liste a arbul. Al è pussibil aumentâ lis sôs funzions cui plugins e i scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Nautilus offre toutes les fonctionnalités basiques et avancées d’un gestionnaire de fichiers. Il peut rechercher et gérer vos fichiers et dossiers, locaux ou sur un réseau, lire et écrire des données vers des médias amovibles, exécuter des scripts et des applications. Il présente trois vues : grille d’icônes, liste d’icônes, et liste arborescente. Ses fonctionnalités peuvent être étendues avec des greffons et des scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Nautilus tukee kaikkia tiedostonhallintasovellusten perustoimintoja. Sen avulla voit etsiä ja hallita niin paikallisia kuin verkossa olevia tiedostoja sekä kansioita, lukea ja kirjoittaa tietoa erillisiin tallennusvälineisiin, suorittaa komentosarjoja ja käynnistää sovelluksia. Se tukee kolmea eri näkymää: kuvakeruudukko, kuvakeluettelo ja puuluettelo. Sovelluksen toimintaa on mahdollista laajentaa liitännäisillä ja komentosarjoilla.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fa">ناتیلوس تمام توابع پایه‌ای یک مدیر پرونده و بیش‌تر از آن را پشتیبانی می‌کند. این برنامه می‌تواند پرونده‌ها و شاخه‌هایتان را چه به صورت محلّی و چه روی شبکه جست‌وجو و مدیریت کند، داده‌ها را از رسانه‌های قابل حمل خوانده و رویشان بنویسد و کدنوشته‌ها و برنامه‌ها را اجرا کند. این برنامه سه نما دارد: شبکهٔ نقشک، فهرست نقشک و فهرست درختی. توابع این برنامه می‌تواند به‌دست افزایه‌ها و کدنوشته‌ها گسترش یابد.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Nautilus-ek fitxategi-kudeatzaile baten oinarrizko funtzio guztiak eta gehiago eskaintzen ditu. Zure fitxategiak eta karpetak bilatu eta kudeatu ditzake, bai lokalean baita sarean ere. Datuak euskarri aldagarrietatik irakurri eta idatzi ditzake, scriptak exekutatu eta aplikazioak abiarazi. Hiru ikuspegi ditu: ikonoen sareta, ikonoen zerrenda eta zuhaitzaren zerrenda. Bere gaitasunak hedatu daitezke pluginen eta scripten bidez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Nautilus toetab kõiki failihalduri põhifunktsioone ning palju enam. See oskab otsida ja hallata nii kohalikke kui võrguressurssidel asuvaid faile, lugeda ja kirjutada andmeid välistele andmekandjatele, käivitada skripte ja rakendusi. Sellel on kolm vaadet: ikoonide ruudustik, ikoonide loetelu ja puuvaade. Nautiluse võimalusi saab laiendada pluginate ja skriptidega.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Nautilus soporta todas las funciones básicas de un gestor de archivos y algunas más. Puede buscar y gestionar sus archivos y carpeta, tanto locales como remotas, leer y escribir datos de y en dispositivos extraíbles, ejecutar scripts y lanzar aplicaciones. Tiene tres vistas: rejilla de iconos, lista de iconos y árbol. Se puede ampliar su funcionalidad con scripts y complementos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Naŭtilo subtenas ĉiujn bazajn funkciojn de dosieradministrilo kaj pli. Ĝi povas serĉi kaj mastrumi viajn dosierojn kaj dosierujojn, kaj loke kaj surrete, legi kaj skribi datumojn al kaj el demeteblaj datumportiloj, ruli skriptojn, kaj lanĉi aplikaĵojn. Ĝi havas tri vidojn: Bildsimbola krado, bildsimbola listo, kaj arba listo. Oni povas etendi ĝiajn funkciojn per kromprogramoj kaj skriptoj.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en_GB">Nautilus supports all the basic functions of a file manager and more. It can search and manage your files and folders, both locally and on a network, read and write data to and from removable media, run scripts, and launch applications. It has three views: Icon Grid, Icon List, and Tree List. Its functions can be extended with plugins and scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Ο Ναυτίλος υποστηρίζει όλες τις βασικές λειτουργίες ενός διαχειριστή αρχείων. Μπορεί να ψάξει και να διαχειριστεί τα αρχεία και τους φακέλους σας, τόσο τοπικά όσα και μέσω του δικτύου, να διαβάσει και να γράψει δεδομένα από αφαιρούμενες συσκευές, να εκτελέσει σενάρια ενεργειών, και να εκκινήσει εφαρμογές. Έχει τρεις προβολές: Πλέγμα εικονιδίων, Λίστα εικονιδίων και Δενδρική λίστα. Οι λειτουργίες του μπορούν να επεκταθούν με πρόσθετα και δέσμες ενεργειών.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Nautilus unterstützt alle grundlegenden Funktionen einer Dateiverwaltung und mehr. Es kann nach lokalen und im Netzwerk gelegenen Dateien und Ordnern suchen und diese verwalten, Daten von entfernbaren Medien lesen und schreiben, Skripte ausführen und Anwendungen starten. Es bietet drei Ansichten: Objekte im Raster, als Liste und die Baumliste. Weitere Funktionen können Plugins und Skripte liefern.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">Nautilus understøtter alle de grundlæggende funktioner til filhåndtering med mere. Programmet kan søge blandt og håndtere dine filer og mapper både lokalt og på et netværk, læse og skrive data til og fra flytbare medier, køre scripter samt starte programmer. Det har tre visningsformer: ikongitter, ikonliste og træliste. Dets funktioner kan udvides med moduler og scripter.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Podporuje všechny základní funkce očekávané od správce souborů a k tomu něco navíc. Umí vyhledávat a spravovat vaše soubory a složky, jak místní, tak síťové, číst a zapisovat data z/na výměnná média, spouštět skripty a aplikace. Má tři způsoby zobrazení: ikony v mřížce, seznam s ikonami a stromové zobrazení. Funkčnost je možné rozšiřovat pomocí zásuvných modulů a skriptů.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca@valencia">El Nautilus permet realitzar totes les funcions bàsiques d'un gestor de fitxers i molt més. Pot buscar i gestionar els vostres fitxers i carpetes, tant locals com a la xarxa; llegir i escriure dades des d'i cap a un medi extraïble; executar scripts i iniciar aplicacions. Té tres visualitzacions: graella d'icones, llista d'icones i llista d'arbre. Es poden ampliar les seues funcions mitjançant connectors i scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Nautilus permet realitzar totes les funcions bàsiques d'un gestor de fitxers i molt més. Pot cercar i gestionar els vostres fitxers i carpetes, tan locals com a la xarxa; llegir i escriure dades des de i cap a un medi extraïble; executar scripts i iniciar aplicacions. Té tres visualitzacions: graella d'icones, llista d'icones i llista d'arbre. Es poden ampliar les seves funcions mitjançant connectors i scripts.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Nautilus podržava sve osnovne funkcije upravitelja datoteka i još mnogo toga. Njime se može pretraživati i upravljanje datotekama i mapama, lokalno i na mreži, čitati i pisati podatke i iz prijenosnih medija, pokretati skripte i pokretati programe. On ima tri pogleda: Ikona rešetke, ikona popis, i stablo popis. Njegova funkcija može se produžiti uz dodataka i skripti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bn_IN">Nautilus, একটি ফাইল ম্যানেজারের সকল প্রাথমিক বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং আরো অনেক কিছু সমর্থন করে। এটি আপনার ফাইল এবং ফোল্ডারগুলি অনুসন্ধান এবং ব্যবস্থাপনা করতে পারে, স্থানীয় এবং একটি নেটওয়ার্ক - উভয় ভাবেই, অপসারণযোগ্য মিডিয়াতে বা থেকে ডেটা পড়তে এবং লিখতে পারে, স্ক্রিপ্ট চালাতে পারে এবং অ্যাপ্লিকেশন লঞ্চ করতে পারে। এটির তিনটি রূপ রয়েছে: আইকন গ্রিড, আইকন তালিকা, এবং ট্রি তালিকা। এটির কার্যকারিতা প্লাগইন এবং স্ক্রিপ্ট দিয়ে বাড়ানো যেতে পারে।</p>
    <p xml:lang="bg">Наутилус предоставя основните и допълнителни функции на файлов мениджър. С тази програма можете да търсите и управлявате файлове и папки — както локално, така и по мрежата, да четете и записвате данни върху външни носители, да изпълнявате скриптове и да стартирате приложения. Наутилус разполага с три изгледа — решетка с икони, списък с икони и дървовиден. Тази програма може да се обогатява със скриптове и разширения.</p>
    <p xml:lang="be">Наўтылус падтрымлівае ўсе звычайныя функцыі кіраўніка файлаў ды многія іншыя. Ён падтрымлівае пошук і кіраванне файламі і папкамі, як лакальнымі, так і сеткавымі, чытанне і запіс даных на пераносных носьбітах, запуск загадных сцэнарыяў, запуск праграм. Праграма мае тры рэжыму працы: у выглядзе сеткі, іх спіса або іерархіі папак. Наўтылус падтрымлівае пашырэнне яго функцый з дапамогай плугінаў і сцэнарыяў.</p>
    <p xml:lang="as">Nautilus এ এটা ফাইল ব্যৱস্থাপকৰ সকলো মৌলিক ফলন আৰু অধিক সমৰ্থন কৰে। ই আপোনাৰ ফাইল আৰু ফোল্ডাৰ সন্ধান আৰু ব্যৱস্থাপনা কৰিব পাৰে, স্থানীয়ভাৱে আৰু নেটৱৰ্কত, আতৰাব পৰা মাধ্যমৰ পৰা তথ্য পঢ়িব আৰু লিখিব পাৰে, স্ক্ৰিপ্টবোৰ চলাব পাৰে, আৰু এপ্লিকেচনসমূহ লঞ্চ কৰিব পাৰে। ইয়াৰ তিনিটা দৰ্শন আছে: আইকন গ্ৰিড, আইকন তালিকা, আৰু ট্ৰি তালিকা। ইয়াৰ কাৰ্য্যকৰীতাক প্লাগিনসমূহ আৰু স্ক্ৰিপ্টসমূহৰ সহায়ত প্ৰসাৰিত কৰিব পাৰি।</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">يدعم نوتلس كل الوظائف الأساسية لمدير سطح المكتب بالإضافة إلى خصائص أخرى. يمكنك البحث في ملفاتك و مجلداتك و إدارتها، محليًا أو عبر الشبكة، و قراءة و كتابة البيانات من و إلى الوسائط المنفصلة، و تشغيل البرامج. لنوتلس ثلاث منظورات: شبكة الأيقونات، و قائمة الأيقونات، و القائمة الشجرية. يمكنك توسيع خصائصه باستخدام الملحقات.</p>
    <p xml:lang="an">Nautilus suporta todas as funcions basicas d'un chestor de fichers y qualques mas. Puede buscar y chestionar os suyos fichers y carpetas, tanto locals como remotas, leyer y escribir datos de y en dispositivos extraíbles, executar scripts y lanzar aplicacions. Tiene tres vistas: reixeta d'iconos, lista d'iconos y arbol. Se puede enamplar a suya funcionalidat con scripts y complementos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="af">Nautilus ondersteun al die basiese funksies van 'n lêerbestuurder en nog vele meer. Dit kan jou lêers en gidse plaaslik of deur die netwerk deursoek en bestuur, data na en van verwyderbare media skryf, skripte uitvoer en programme begin. Dit het drie aansigte: Ikoonrooster, Ikoon Lys, en Boom Lys. Die funksies kan uitgebrei word met inproppe en skripte.</p>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/jishanshaikh4/nautilus/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://wiki.gnome.org/action/show/Apps/Nautilus/</url>
  <url type="help">https://wiki.gnome.org/action/show/Apps/Nautilus</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://wiki.gnome.org/action/show/Apps/Nautilus</url>
  <url type="translate">https://wiki.gnome.org/TranslationProject</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.gnome.NautilusDevel.desktop</launchable>
  <releases>
    <release version="41.1" date="2021-12-31"/>
  </releases>
  <project_group>GNOME</project_group>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <developer_name>The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="zh_TW">GNOME 專案</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="zh_CN">GNOME 项目</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="vi">Dự án GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="uk">Проєкт GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="tr">GNOME Projesi</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sv">GNOME-projektet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sr">Гномов пројекат</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sl">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sk">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ru">Проект GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ro">Proiectul GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt_BR">O Projeto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt">O Projeto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pl">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pa">ਗਨੋਮ ਪਰੋਜੈੱਕਟ</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="oc">Lo projècte GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nl">Het Gnome-project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ne">जिनोम परियोजना</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nb">GNOME prosjektet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ms">Projek GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="mjw">GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="lv">GNOME projekts</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="lt">GNOME projektas</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ko">그놈 프로젝트</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="kk">GNOME жобасы</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ja">The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="it">Il progetto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="is">GNOME verkefnið</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="id">Proyek GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hu">A GNOME projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hr">GNOME projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="he">מיזם GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="gl">O Proxecto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fur">Il progjet GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fr">Le projet GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fi">Gnome-projekti</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fa">پروژهٔ گنوم</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eu">GNOME proiektua</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="es">El Proyecto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eo">La Projekto GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="en_GB">The GNOME Project</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="el">Το έργο GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="de">Das GNOME-Projekt</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="da">GNOME-projektet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="cs">Projekt GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ckb">پرۆژەی گنۆم</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca">El projecte GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="bn_IN">জিনোম প্রকল্প</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="bg">Проектът GNOME</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="be">Праект GNOME</developer_name>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://static.gnome.org/appdata/nautilus/nautilus-201901141.png</image>
      <caption>Tile View</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_TW">鋪排檢視</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_CN">平铺视图</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="vi">Lát gạch</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Перегляд мозаїкою</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Döşeme Görünümü</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Ikonvy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr">Преглед плочица</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Mrežni pogled</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Zobrazenie dlaždíc</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">В виде значков</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Vizualizare titlu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt_BR">Visão lado a lado</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Vista de mosaico</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Widok ikon</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pa">ਟਾਈਲ ਝਲਕ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="oc">Vista en lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Tegelweergave</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ne">टायल दृश्य</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nb">Flisvisning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ms">Pandangan Jubin</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lv">Mozaīkas skats</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lt">Piktogramų rodinys</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">격자 보기</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kk">Плитка көрінісі</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kab">Sken-d azwel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ja">タイル表示</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Vista a icone</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="is">Reitasýn</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Tampilan Ubin</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hu">Csempenézet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hr">Popločani prikaz</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">תצוגת אריחים</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Vista de teselas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fur">Viodude a mosaic</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Vue en mosaïque</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Laattanäkymä</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fa">نمای عنوان</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Lauza-ikuspegia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Vista de mosaico</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Kahela vido</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_GB">Tile View</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Προβολή σε πλακίδια</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Kachelansicht</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="da">Flisevisning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Dlaždicové zobrazení</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ckb">پیشاندنای تەخت</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Vista en mosaic</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn_IN">টাইল ভিউ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Изглед като плочки</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be">Рэжым значкоў</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://static.gnome.org/appdata/nautilus/nautilus-201901142.png</image>
      <caption>List View</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zu">Isibonisi Sohlu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_TW">清單檢視</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_HK">清單檢視</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_CN">列表视图</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="yo">Òye Àtòjọ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="xh">Okubonakalayo Kuluhlu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="wa">Vuwe e djivêye</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="vi">Danh sách</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uz@cyrillic">Рўйхат кўриниши</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uz">Roʻyxat koʻrinishi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Перегляд списком</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ug">تىزىم كۆرۈنۈش</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Liste Görünümü</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tk">List Görnöşi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="th">มุมมองแบบรายชื่อ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tg">Намуди рӯйхат</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="te">జాబితా వీక్షణం</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ta">பட்டியல் காட்சி</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Listvy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr@latin">Prikaži kao spisak</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr@ije">Прегледај као списак</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr">Прикажи као списак</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sq">Paraqitje në formë liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Seznamski prikaz</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Zobrazenie zoznamu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="si">ලැයිස්තු දසුන</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">В виде списка</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Vizualizare listă</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt_BR">Visão em lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Vista de lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ps">لړ کوت</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Widok listy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pa">ਲਿਸਟ ਝਲਕ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="or">ତାଲିକା ପ୍ରଦର୍ଶନ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="oc">Vista en lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nso">Tebelelo ya Lelokelelo</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Vis som liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Lijstweergave</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ne">सूची दृश्य</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nds">Listansicht</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nb">Listevisning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ms">Pandangan Senarai</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mr">यादी दाखवा</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mn">Жагсаалт хэлбэрээр харах</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ml">നാമാവലി കാഴ്ച</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mk">Поглед на листа</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mi">Tiro Rārangi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mg">Fijerin'ny lisitra</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mai">सूची दृश्य</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lv">Saraksta skats</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lt">Sąrašo vaizdas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ln">Monisa liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="li">Liesweergaaf</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ky">Тизме түрүндө көрүү</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ku">Nîşandana Lîsteyê</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">목록 보기</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kn">ಪಟ್ಟಿ ನೋಟ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kk">Тізім көрінісі</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kab">Tamuɣli s tebdart</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">სიისებრი ხედი</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ja">一覧表示</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Vista a elenco</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="is">Listasýn</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ig">Ngosi ndesịta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Tampilan Tabel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hy">Ցանկի տեսաբերում</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hu">Listanézet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hr">Pogled popisa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hi">सूची दृश्य</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">תצוגת רשימה</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ha">Kallo na Jeri</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gv">Reayrt Rolley</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gu">યાદી દૃશ્ય</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Visualización en lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gd">Sealladh liosta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ga">Amharc Liosta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fur">Viodude a liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Vue en liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Luettelonäkymä</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fa">نمای فهرستی</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Zerrenda-ikuspegia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Nimekirjavaade</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Vista de lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Lista vido</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en@shaw">𐑤𐑦𐑕𐑑 𐑝𐑿</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_GB">List View</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_CA">List View</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Προβολή λίστας</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="dz">ཐོ་ཡིག་གི་མཐོང་སྣང་།</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Listenansicht</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="da">Listevisning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cy">Golwg Rhestr</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Seznamové zobrazení</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="crh">Liste Körünimi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ckb">پیشاندانی لیستەیی</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca@valencia">Vista de llista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Vista de llista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bs">Pregled liste</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="br">Gwel dre roll</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bo">ཐོ་འགོད་ལྟ་ཀློག</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn_IN">তালিকা অনুসারে প্রদর্শন</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn">তালিকা অনুসারে প্রদর্শন</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Изглед като списък</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be@latin">Vyhlad śpisu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be">Рэжым спіса</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="az">Sıra Görünüşü</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ast">Vista de llista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="as">তালিকা অনুসৰি প্ৰদৰ্শন</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">منظور القائمة</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="an">Vista de lista</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="am">ዝርዝር ዕይታ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="af">Lysaangesig</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://static.gnome.org/appdata/nautilus/nautilus-201901143.png</image>
      <caption>Search</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_TW">搜尋</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_HK">搜尋</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_CN">搜索</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="vi">Tìm kiếm</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uz@cyrillic">Қидириш</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uz">Qidirish</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Пошук</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ug">ئىزدە</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Arama</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="th">ค้นหา</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tg">Ҷустуҷӯ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="te">వెతుకు</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ta">தேடு</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Sök</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr@latin">Pretraga</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr">Претрага</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sq">Kërko</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Iskanje</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Vyhľadať</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="si">සොයන්න</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Поиск</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Caută</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt_BR">Pesquisa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Procurar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ps">لټون</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Wyszukiwanie</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pa">ਖੋਜ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="or">ଖୋଜନ୍ତୁ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="oc">Recercar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Søk</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Zoekopdracht</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ne">खोजी गर्नुहोस्</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nds">Sök</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nb">Søk</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="my">ရှာဖွေရေး</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ms">Cari</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mr">शोधा</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ml">തിരയുക</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mk">Пребарување</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mjw">Kiri</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mg">Karohy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="mai">खोजू</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lv">Meklēt</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lt">Ieškoti</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ln">Boluki</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ky">Издөө</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ku">Lêgerîn</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">검색</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kn">ಹುಡುಕು</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="km">ស្វែងរក</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kk">Іздеу</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kab">Nadi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ძებნა</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ja">検索</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Cerca</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="is">Leita</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="io">Serchez</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Cari</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hu">Keresés</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hr">Pretraga</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hi">ढूंढें</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">חיפוש</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gv">Shirrey</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gu">શોધો</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Buscar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gd">Lorg</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ga">Cuardaigh</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fy">Sykje</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fur">Cîr</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Recherche</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Etsi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fa">جست‌وجو</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Bilatu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Otsing</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Buscar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Serĉi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en@shaw">𐑕𐑻𐑗</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_GB">Search</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_CA">Search</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Αναζήτηση</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="dz">འཚོལ་ཞིབ།</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Suchen</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="da">Søg</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cy">Chwilio</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Hledat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="crh">Qıdıruv</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ckb">گەڕان</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca@valencia">Busca</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Cerca</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bs">Pretraga</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="br">Klask</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bo">འཚོལ་བཤེར</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn_IN">অনুসন্ধান</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn">অনুসন্ধান</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Търсене</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be@latin">Pošuk</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be">Пошук</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ast">Guetar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="as">সন্ধান</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">ابحث</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="an">Mirar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="af">Soek</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://static.gnome.org/appdata/nautilus/nautilus-201901144.png</image>
      <caption>Other Locations</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_TW">其他的位置</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh_CN">其他位置</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="vi">Vị trí khác</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Інші адреси</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Diğer Konumlar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="th">ตำแหน่งอื่น</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Andra platser</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr@latin">Druga mesta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sr">Друга места</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Druga mesta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Ostatné umiestnenia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Другие места</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Alte locații</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt_BR">Outros locais</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Outras localizações</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Inne położenia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pa">ਹੋਰ ਟਿਕਾਣੇ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="oc">Autres emplaçaments</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Andere locaties</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ne">अन्य स्थानहरू</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nb">Andre lokasjoner</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ms">Lokasi Lain</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ml">മറ്റുള്ള സ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lv">Citas vietas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="lt">Kitos vietos</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ln">Bisika mosusu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">다른 위치</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kk">Басқа орналасулар</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="kab">Idiganen-nniḍen</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ja">他の場所</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Altre posizioni</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="is">Aðrar staðsetningar</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Lokasi Lain</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hu">Egyéb helyek</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="hr">Ostale lokacije</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">מיקומים אחרים</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Outras localizacións</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gd">Ionadan eile</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ga">Suíomhanna Eile</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fur">Altris posizions</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Autres emplacements</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Muut sijainnit</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fa">دیگر مکان‌ها</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Beste kokalekuak</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Otras ubicaciones</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Aliaj lokoj</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en_GB">Other Locations</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Άλλες τοποθεσίες</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Andere Orte</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="da">Andre placeringer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Další umístění</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ckb">شوێنی تر</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca@valencia">Altres ubicacions</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Altres ubicacions</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bn_IN">অন্যান্য অবস্থান</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Други местоположения</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="be">Іншыя месцы</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">أماكن أخرى</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="af">Ander liggings</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <update_contact>nautilus-list@gnome.org</update_contact>
  <translation type="gettext">nautilus</translation>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>Notifications</kudo>
    <kudo>SearchProvider</kudo>
  </kudos>
</component>
